《速度与激情》
Just packed up a real money load, and it's coming your way.
卡车上装满了值钱的货 正朝你的方向开去
Look for "Rodgers" on the side of the truck.
在卡车侧面 写着“罗杰”的就是目标物
Don't forget my share of the deal.
别忘了我那一份
Shit!
该死！
(杜洛托咖啡屋)
- Tuna on white, no crust, right? - I don't know. How is it?
- 去边的鲔鱼三明治  对不对？ - 我还没决定  今天的好吃吗？
Every day for the last three weeks you've been coming in here...
在过去的三个礼拜中
and you've been asking me how the tuna is.
你天天问我鲔鱼三明治好不好吃
It was crappy yesterday...
昨天很糟糕
it was crappy the day before, and guess what.
前天也不怎么样
- It hasn't changed. - I'll have the tuna.
- 今天还是一样 - 那就来份鲔鱼三明治吧
- No crust? - No crust.
- 要去边吗？ - 是的
Thank you.
谢谢你
Talk to me, Jesse. This ain't workir, brother.
这部车是有点不对劲 杰西  你看是什么毛病
It's your fuel map. It's got a nasty hole.
应该是燃料系统漏油的问题
- It's why you're unloading in third. - I told you it was third.
- 所以在第三档就上不去 - 我就说是第三档吧
I lengthen the injector pulse another millisec...
我把脉冲喷油嘴加长一毫秒
and just tune the NOS timer, you'll run nines.
再调整氧化亚氮燃油注入器 问题就解决了
What's up with this fool? What is he, sandwich crazy?
这个傻瓜怎么回事 吃三明治好像吃上瘾了
No, V. He ain't here for the food.
他才不是为吃而来
Chill out, bro. He's just slinging parts for Harry.
少胡扯 他是哈瑞新雇的销售员
- I know what he's slinging. - He's trying to get in Mia's pants.
- 我知道他想干什么 - 他想和蜜雅上床
- What's up, guys? - How you doing, Mia?
- 你们怎么样？ - 蜜雅  你好吗？
How you livir, girl?
你还是活的那么刺激吗？
Hey, Dom. You want something to drink?
唐  要饮料吗？
Ah, he's beautiful.
他挺帅的嘛
I like his haircut.
我喜欢他的发型
Vince.
文斯
Vince!
文斯！
- What? - Can I get you anything?
- 干什么？ - 你要吃什么？
You look good.
你今天很漂亮
Thanks a lot, Mia. See you tomorrow.
谢谢你  蜜雅  明天见
Sure.
好的
- Tomorrow? - Oh, I love this part.
- 明天？ - 我最喜欢这一段 不行
Try Fatburger from now on.
从现在起你改吃汉堡
You can get yourself a double-cheese with fries for 2.95, faggot.
只要两块九毛五就能吃一客 双层起司汉堡和薯条  死玻璃
- I like the tuna here. - Bullshit. No one likes the tuna.
- 我喜欢这里的鲔鱼三明治 - 胡说  没有人喜欢
Well, I do.
我就喜欢
Jesus Christ, Dom! Would you get out there?
天呐！唐  你过来一下好吗？
I'm sick of this shit! I'm not kidding, Dom!
烦死人了 告诉你我可不是开玩笑的
Get out there!
快去呀！
- What'd you put in that sandwich? - That's really funny.
- 你在三明治里放了什么东西 - 你以为自己很幽默
Dom!
唐！
All right.
好啦
- He was in my face. - I'm in your face.
- 他在我面前张牙舞爪 - 现在是我在你面前
Relax! Don't push it! You embarrass me!
行啦  少逞强 你太让我没面子了
Get over there!
到那边去
Jesse, give me the wallet.
杰西  把他的皮夹给我
"Brian Earl Spilner." Sounds like a serial killer name.
“布莱恩厄尔史皮尼” 像个杀人犯的名字
- Is that what you are? - No, man.
- 你是杀人犯吗？ - 不是
Don't come around here again.
以后不准再来这里
Hey, man, you know this is bullshit.
我有行动的自由
- You work for Harry, right? - Yeah, I just started.
- 你是替哈瑞做事吗？ - 对  才刚开始上班
You were just fired.
你已经被开除了
(赛车边缘 高性能汽车零件)
Hey, Dominic, I appreciate what you did in a big way.
唐老大 谢谢你大批的向我买货
Dominic, I owe you.
我永远记得你的恩惠
Brian, you're messing with my business.
布莱恩  你想让我关门吗
When Dominic drives, he's golden.
只要唐老大开车  他就是财神
Kids pour in here, want everything he has, every performance part...
大家都跑来买他所用的零件
and they pay cash!
而且都是付现金的
- What did Dominic say? - You don't wanna know.
- 唐说了些什么？ - 你不会爱听的
- What did Dominic say? - He wants you outta here.
- 他到底说了什么？ - 他要你滚蛋
- He wants me outta here? - Yes!
- 他要我滚蛋？ - 没错
- And what did you say to Dom? - What do you think I said?
- 那你又怎么说呢？ - 你想我能说什么？
I told him, "Good help is hard to find."
我只能说“好帮手很难请”
Relax.
你放心
I need NOS.
我需要氧化亚氮燃油注入系统
- I need NOS. - No.
- 我要氧化亚氮燃油注入系统  - 不行
My car topped out at 140 miles per hour this morning.
今早我开到 时速140英里时就上不去了
Amateurs don't use nitrous oxide.
业余的人不用氧化亚氮
I've seen the way you drive. You got a heavy foot.
我见过你开车 你的脚不够灵活
- You'll blow yourself to pieces. - I need one of these.
- 如果不改  迟早会出事 - 给我一个这种装置
One of the big ones.
要大的那种
Actually, no. Let's make it two.
等一下  给我两个吧
And, Harry, I need it by tonight.
还有今晚我就要
Hey, hold up, hold up. Look at this snowman right here, man.
嘿  等一下 居然有个白小子出现
Sweet ride. What you running under there, man?
喂  你的车都有什么装备
- Making me find out the hard way? - Hell, yeah.
- 想让我自己去发掘吗？ - 当然啦
You brave. You brave. They call me Hector.
真勇敢  我叫海克特
I got a last name too, but I can't pronounce it, so...
我也有姓  但太难念  所以…
Brian Spilner.
我是布莱恩
Typical white boy name. Know what I'm saying?
典型的白人名字 你懂我的意思吧
See that over there?
你看到那边那辆车吗？
That's mine. It's my baby. But I ain't cutting her loose tonight.
那是我的 不过今晚我不参加赛车
- Why not? - 'Cause I'm going legit.
- 为什么？ - 因为我想参加正统赛车
Trying to get on the NI RA circuit. You heard about that?
我想参加劲爆拖车赛 你听过吗？
Hell, yeah.
当然听过
- So what's up with you, man? - I'm just waiting for Toretto.
- 你想干什么？ - 我在等杜洛托
Shit. Better get in line.
大家都在等他
- This yours? - Yeah. I'm standing next to it.
- 这是你的车？ - 是呀  我不正站在它旁边吗
That's funny. You know, Edwin happens to know a few things.
妙得很 有几件事或许你还不知道
And one of the things Edwin knows is...
其中之一就是
it's not how you stand by your car.
你站不站在车旁不重要
It's how you race your car. You better learn that.
重要的是你怎么赛车 老兄  最好搞清楚
Oh, shit. Here they come. It's on.
喔  他们来了  要开始罗
- Dom, how you doing? - Hey, Camille.
- 唐  你好 - 嗨  卡美儿
You been doing yoga?
你在练瑜珈吗？
You did? Of course you did. Monica.
真的呀？ 当然是真的  蒙妮卡！
I smell skanks.
我闻到一股狐骚味
Why don't you pack it up before I leave tread marks on your face?
再不走 小心我在你们脸上留点记号
- Letty, I was just talking. - Whatever.
- 莱蒂  我们只是聊聊天 - 是哟！
Okay, Hector.
海克特
Yeah? What's up, man?
老大  有什么事？
- What's up? - Edwin.
- 怎么样？ - 艾德温
- How we doing this tonight? - One race.
- 今晚怎么比？ - 只赛一场
Two-G buy-in. Winner takes all.
赌注两千美金  赢的人全拿
- Hector, you're gonna hold the cash. - Why Hector?
- 海克特  你来管钱 - 为什么由海克特管钱？
He's too slow to make away with the money.
他的车最慢 就算偷钱也跑不远
- Good luck, guys. - Wait. Hold up.
- 祝你们好运 - 等等
I don't have any cash, but I do have the pink slip to my car.
我虽然没现金 但是我有车主证
You just can't climb in the ring with Ali 'cause you think you box.
你以为会拳击 就是拳王阿里的对手吗
He knows I can box.
他知道我打得好
So check it out. It's like this.
我有个提议
I lose, the winner takes my car, clean and clear.
谁赢我  我的车就是他的
But if I win, I take the cash, and I take the respect.
但若我赢了  不但拿钱 也希望能赢得你们的尊敬
Respect.
尊敬
To some people, that's more important.
对某些人来说尊敬蛮重要的
That your car?
那是你的车？
I see a cool-air intake.
这里有一个空气压缩器
It's got a NOS-fogger system and a T-four turbo, Dominic.
一个氧化亚氮雾化系统 和四缸涡轮增压引擎
I see an AIC controller.
还有AlC控制器
It has direct port nitrous injection.
直接接到氧化亚氮的喷气嘴
Yeah, and a stand-alone fuel management system.
还有一个独立的燃料控制系统
Not a bad way to spend $10,000.
恐怕要花上一万块美金
You see that shit?
你看到了吗？
He's got enough NOS in there to blow himself up, period.
那么多的氧化亚氮 足够把他炸成碎片
What do you say? Am I won'thy?
你说我值不值？
We don't know yet. But you're in.
现在还不知道 不过你可以参加比赛
Let's go.
咱们走
What the hell's going on around here?
到底发生了什么事？
Street's closed, pizza boy. Find another way home.
这条路不通  你另外找路吧
Goddamn street racers.
混蛋的飙车族
Iog on 22, code three. Tension is high.
注意  这里情况很紧张
They've blocked the street.
他们把街道封锁了
Edwin...
艾德温
this is yours, whether you win or lose.
不管你赢或输  我都是你的
But if you win, you get her too.
但是如果你赢了  她也是你的
You're gonna win.
你一定会赢
I'm gonna win.
我绝对会赢
We had a reported homicide, 187, at Barakian liquor.
接到报告 巴拉肯杂货店发生命案
I've got a 187 in Glendale. Cops are all over it.
格兰岱尔发生命案 警察全部出动
We're good to roll. I repeat, good to roll.
我们可以开始了 我再重复一次  可以开始了
- Let's race! - Right.
- 我们开始赛车吧 - 好
Go!
出发！
Hell, yeah!
太棒了！
Damn, that guy's fast.
天呀  那家伙可真快
Let's go! "Menage A"!
我们急起直追  “加油呀”！
No! Monica!
完了  蒙妮卡泡汤啦
(警告 危险！)
Shut up!
安静点！
Let's go now, baby!
加油呀！
- Here's what you want, right here. - There you go.
- 你要的全在这里 - 给你
You were racing a bunch of skateboards.
你在和一群小鬼头赛车嘛
My sister holds the money.
把钱交给我妹妹
Count it.
你要数清楚
And you're my trophy.
你就是我的奖品
Hey, Monica! What's up, baby?
蒙妮卡宝贝  怎么样呀？
What's your problem, nigga? You didn't win.
你有毛病吗  又没有赢
Fuck you, then!
去你的！
- Was that fun? - Got a problem there, huh, buddy?
- 你觉得好玩吗？ - 老弟  麻烦大了
- What are you smiling about? - Dude, I almost had you.
- 你傻笑个什么劲 - 我几乎赢了你
You almost had me?
你几乎赢我？
You never had me. You never had your car.
你没赢过我 连车也不是你的了
Granny shifting, not double-clutching like you should.
你换档时乱来一通 哪有那样踩双重离合器的
You're lucky that hundred-shot of NOS didn't blow the welds on the intake.
好在氧化亚氮 没把空气压缩器给烧掉
Almost had me?
居然敢说几乎赢我
Now me and the mad scientist gotta rip apart the block...
现在我和我的天才科学家 得把这部车拆开
and replace the piston rings you fried.
好把被你烧掉的活塞环给换掉
Ask any racer, any real racer.
你去问问 任何一位真正的赛车手
It don't matter if you win by an inch or a mile.
不管你是赢一英寸或一英里
Winning's winning.
赢就是赢
Available units, we have reported street racing along Hawthorne...
请注意  接到报告 在哈松区有飙车族在赛车…
Oh, shit! We got cops!
要命！警察来了
Go!
快走！
Dom, get in the car! Go!
唐  上车  快走！
Toretto, stop right there!
杜洛托  站住不准走！
Get in!
上车！
You're the last person in the world I expected to show up.
没想到居然是你来救我
I thought if I got in your good graces, you might let me keep my car.
我想若能得到你的赏识 或许你会让我保留这部车
You are in my good graces, but you ain't keeping your car.
你是得到我的赏识 可惜我还是要你的车
You drive like you've done this before. What are you, a wheel man?
你车开得不错 以前是开车的吗？
No
不是
You boost cars?
那是偷车贼罗
- No. Never. - Ever done time?
- 不是 - 坐过牢吗？
Couple of overnighters. No big deal.
只进去过夜而已 没什么大不了的
What about the two years in juvie for boosting cars?
你不是曾为了偷车 在感化院待过两年吗？
Tucson, right?
在图桑对不对？
Yeah, I had Jesse run a profile on you, Brian Earl Spilner.
没错  我叫杰西去查你的资料
He'll find anything on the Web, anything about anybody.
如今你可以在网站上 找到任何资料
So why bullshit?
你何必去骗人？
So what about you?
那你呢？
Two years in Lompoc.
在隆波克坐了两年牢
I'll die before I go back.
我宁愿死也不要回去
- Oh, great. - What?
- 真倒霉  - 怎么了？
It's gonna be a long-ass night, that's what.
今晚将是个漫长的一夜
Follow us.
跟我们走
(哲学家孔子)
I thought we had an agreement.
我们不是已达成协议了吗
You stay away, I stay away.
你走你的路  我过我的桥
Everybody stays happy.
大家都高兴
We got lost, Johnny. What do you want me to tell you?
强尼  你要我怎么说呢 我们迷路了
- Who's  "we"? - My new mechanic.
- 他是谁？ - 我新请的技工
Brian, meetJohnny Tran.
布莱恩  这位是强尼
The guy in the snakeskin pants, that's his cousin, Lance.
穿蛇皮裤的那位是蓝斯 是他的表弟
So when are you gonna give me a shot at that Honda 2000 of yours?
什么时候能 和你那部本田2000赛车呢？
- This your ride? - It was. It's his now.
- 这是你的车  - 本来是我的  现在是他的了
No, it's not. I haven't taken delivery.
不是  我还没有验收
Then it's nobody's car.
所以是无主的车罗
Somebody put in the wrench time.
有人下了不少功夫嘛
- What do you think, Lance? - It's an amazing machine.
- 蓝斯  你说呢？ - 看起来很不错
Yes, indeed.
的确不错
Let's go.
我们走
I'll see you in the desert next month.
下个月摩哈比沙漠见
Be ready to have your ass handed to you.
你一定会输得屁滚尿流
You're gonna need more than that crotch rocket.
就凭这辆摩托车吗？
I got something for you.
到时候你自然会知道
What the hell was that about?
这又是怎么回事？
Long story. I'll tell you later. Let's get outta here.
说来话长  以后再告诉你 我们快走
NOS!
要爆炸了！
So, what the hell was that all about?
到底是怎么回事？
It's a long story.
那是个很长的故事
We got a 20-mile hike. Humor me.
反正有二十英里的路要走 你就慢慢说吧
A business deal that went sour.
一个变质的交易
Plus, I made the mistake of sleeping with his sister.
再加上我不应该和他妹妹上床
Yo, Spilner.
嘿  布莱恩
You want a beer?
要喝啤酒吗？
Oh, shit.
喔！糟糕
We were all there, right? Falling behind.
我们全都落在后面  对不对？
- With all that nitrous. - Yeah.
- 载着那些氧化亚氮 - 对
Yo, Dom. We were just about to go looking for you, brother.
唐  我们正想去找你
- Where were you? - There were mass cops there.
- 你到哪里去了？ - 那里有一大堆的警察
They came in from every direction. Their shit was orchestrated.
他们像排练过的一样 从每个方向开进来
- This your beer? - Yeah, that's my beer.
- 这是你的啤酒？ - 对
Yo, Einstein. Take it upstairs.
我的大天才  带她到楼上去
You can't detail a car with the cover on.
穿着衣服怎么享受嘛
Can't even get that right.
连这种小事也搞不定
You all right?
你没事吧？
Am I all right?
你看我像没事吗？
It was just a question.
我只不过问问罢了
Yo, Dom! Why'd you bring the buster here?
唐  你把那菜鸟带来这里干嘛
'Cause the buster kept me out of handcuffs!
因为那个菜鸟救了我
He didn't just run back to the fort!
他没有忙着逃跑
The buster brought me back.
是他带我回来的
You can have any brew you want... as long as it's a Corona.
只要是可乐娜  啤酒随你喝
- Thanks, man. - That's Vince's, so enjoy it.
- 谢谢你 - 那瓶是文斯的  好好享受吧
You...
你…
Hey, bro, you got a bathroom?
老大  厕所在哪里？
Yeah, upstairs. First door on the right.
楼上右边第一间
He's got no call being up in here.
他没资格来这里
- You don't know that fool for shit! - He's right, Dom.
- 你对他一点也不了解 - 唐  他说的不错
Vince, there was a time when I didn't know you.
文斯 别忘了当初我也不了解你呀
That was in the third grade!
拜托那时候我们才小学三年级
Yeah, so, what girls are here?
那些女人是你找来的吗？
- You name it. You want mine? - You need to shut the f...
- 什么样的都有  要我的吗？ - 你最好闭上…
- You don't have anything? - You look a bit tired.
- 你什么都没有 - 你看起来有点累
I think you should go upstairs and give me a massage.
最好到楼上去替我按摩
Look at all our guests.
可是这些客人怎么办
How about we go upstairs and you give me a massage?
那就到楼上去由你替我按摩
Crazy lady.
疯女人
You know you owe me a ten-second car, right?
记住你还欠我一部十秒内 能跑四分之一英里的极速车
Ouch.
哎哟！
Oh, shit.
有他好看的
Did you wipe the seat?
马桶座垫你有擦干净吗？
Oh, Jesus Christ! Would you cut the shit already?
好啦  你别惹事好吗
Come on!
别这样！
Come on. Let's go get me a drink.
走  替我拿点饮料
Come on, man. We were just about to get along.
别走嘛 我们正在渐渐进入情况
- So, what do you want? - Anything, long as it's cold.
- 你要哪种饮料 - 只要是冰的都行
My brother likes you. He usually doesn't like anybody.
我哥哥喜欢你 通常他谁也不喜欢
Yeah, he's a complicated guy.
对  他蛮难懂的
Yeah? What about you?
是吗？那你呢？
- I'm simpler. - You're a shitty liar.
- 我简单多了 - 你连撒谎都不会
Well, I'll take that as a compliment.
我认为那是恭维
- But there's a problem. - What's that?
- 现在有个问题 - 什么问题？
You need to get some sleep.
你得好好去睡一觉
And you definitely, definitely need a shower.
而且肯定需要洗澡
Come on. I'll take you home.
走  我送你回家
Show me your hands. Very good. Now open the door.
把手伸出来  很好 现在把车门打开
Put your hands on your head. Behind your head.
把手放在头后 放在你头后
Face the front of the vehicle, walk backwards towards the rear.
面向车子  向后倒退到车尾
Take two steps to your right. Stop right there.
向右走两步  停在那里
What'd I do?
我做了什么？
Shut up. He's clean, Sarge.
闭嘴 警官  他没武器
Damn! Muse, will you take these things off?
慕斯  拜托你把手铐拿掉
- Shit. You put 'em on so tight. - I like realism.
- 要命  弄得那么紧 - 要玩就玩真的
- You like realism. - You never know who's watching.
- 玩真的 - 否则万一被人看到就糟了
Nice crib, Sergeant. It's a lot nicer than that last place you confiscated.
真漂亮 比上次被充公的房子要好多了
Ain't it? Eddie Fisher built this house for Elizabeth Taylor in the '50s.
这是艾迪费雪在五零年代 替伊丽莎白泰勒盖的
See? Even the cops are Hollywood in Hollywood.
连好莱坞的警察都有明星架势
Here he is, fresh from Toretto's hot rod heaven.
才把他从 杜洛托极速车天堂带过来
That was an $80,000 vehicle, officer.
那可是部八万美金的车子
- Wait. You tell him what happened? - He knows what happened.
- 等等  你告诉他了吗？ - 他早就知道了
- Send the bill to Johnny Tran. - The kid's giving me attitude?
- 最好把帐单交给强尼 - 你居然跟我耍嘴皮子
That doesn't speak very well for police-FBI relations, Tanner.
这会影响到 警方和FBl之间的关系
- I walk in, the guy's already giving... - All right, all right.
- 我一走进来  他就… - 好了
We'll talk, okay? Let's talk about it.
我们慢慢谈  好吗？
Muse, why don't you make us four iced cappuccinos, please.
慕斯 请你给我们四杯冰卡布其诺
- Come on. - Regular or decaf, Sarge?
- 走吧 - 要普通的还是低咖啡因的
Decaf, I think.
低咖啡因的吧
Four hijackings in two months, and we don't have anything.
两个月内有四件抢劫案 我们一点线索都没有
DVD players and digital cameras alone are won'th a million-two...
单是DVD放映机 和数位照相机就值一、两百万
which brings the grand total to six million plus.
加起来总值超过六百万美金
We're in the political crosshairs now, Brian.
我们的官方压力非常大
That's why you're undercover.
所以才让你去卧底
You want that detective badge fast, kid. And you wanna know something?
告诉你一件事 若你能帮我们结案
The FBI can help, if you come through for us.
升官这件事就包在FBl身上
- What does the truck driver say? - He gave us the same M.O.
- 卡车司机是怎么说的？ - 他给我们同样的描述
Three Honda Civics, precision driving...
一共三辆本田喜美 驾驶技术高超
the same green neon glow from under the chassis.
车身底盘有绿色霓虹灯
Lab says the skid marks came back the same:
根据化验室的报告 刹车痕全都一样
Mashamoto ZX tires.
是藤原正统ZX轮胎
So we know that it's somebody in the street racing world.
所以一定是那些极速车
We don't make this case soon...
我们若不能尽快解决
the truckers will take matters into their own hands.
卡车司机们 就会自己采取激烈的手段
I tell 'em we're close.
我告诉他们已经快结案了
You gonna make me a liar?
难道你要我变成说谎的人
Look, what do we know?
先看看我们已有的资料
We all know this world revolves around Toretto, right?
我们都知道这和杜洛托有关
I'm not saying that he's necessarily the one that's popping these trucks...
虽然不见得是他亲自下的手
but I can guarantee the both of you that he knows who is.
但我保证他绝对知道是谁干的
- It's just a matter of time until... - You want time?
- 我需要时间… - 你需要时间？
Buy the magazine. We don't have time.
我们已经没有时间啦
Just get me something I can use.
尽快给我一些可以用的资料
Is Harry cooperating?
哈瑞有没有好好合作？
Yeah, like a guy who's gonna do time for receiving stolen property if he doesn't.
有  否则就叫他为收购赃物 到牢里去蹲个三、五年
What kind of vibe is he getting from Toretto?
他对杜洛托有什么评语
He's scared of him, but he doesn't think he's jacking trucks in his spare time.
他很怕他  可是不认为 杜洛托会在闲虾时去抢卡车
- He's too controlled for that. - Wait.
- 因为杜洛托很有自制力 - 等一等
Not that I want to contradict Harry's fine judge of character...
不是我不相信哈瑞的观察力
but Toretto did hard time for nearly beating a guy to death.
但当初杜洛托 是因为差点打死人才去坐牢的
He's got nitrous oxide in his blood and a gas tank for a brain.
他血液里充满了氧化亚氮 脑袋里则充满了汽油
Do not turn your back on him.
他绝非善类
Hey, Tanner. I'm gonna need another car.
泰勒  我还需要一部车
What about parts and service?
那零件和服务怎么办？
- Hold off on that. - What should I do with this?
- 先拖延一下 - 我真不知道该怎么办？
All right, what the hell is this?
在搞什么呀
What do you got there?
那是什么玩意？
- This is your car. - My car?
- 你的车呀 - 我的车？
I said a ten-second car, not a ten-minute car.
我要的是 十秒能跑四分之一英里的车
You could push this across the finish line, or tow it.
这家伙只能用推的 或用拖车拖过终点线
Couldrt even tow that across the finish line.
恐怕连拖都拖不过终点
No faith.
这么没信心呀
I have faith in you, but this isn't a junkyard.
我对你有信心 对这堆垃圾可没有
- This is a garage. - Pop the hood.
- 我们这里是汽车修理厂 - 把车盖打开
- Pop the hood? - Pop the hood.
- 把车盖打开？ - 对  打开它
TwoJZ engine.
哇！2JZ引擎
- No shit. - And what did I tell you?
- 这么厉害 - 我不是早就告诉你了吗？
- I retract my previous statement. - You know what?
- 我收回刚刚说的话 - 依我看
This will decimate all after you put about 15 grand in it...
如果投资一万五 若需要隔夜送到的日本零件时
or more, if we have to overnight parts from Japan.
可能要花更多的钱 但保证能打败所有的跑车
We'll put it on my tab at Harry's.
叫哈瑞先记在我的帐上好了
Yes!
好！
I gotta get you racing again so I can make some money off your ass.
我得让你再去参加赛车 好从你身上赚上一笔钱
There's a show in the desert called Race Wars, and that's where you'll do it.
你就去参加在加州 摩哈比沙漠举行的极速大赛
Tell you what. When you're not working at Harry's, you're working here.
以后你下班后就过来帮忙
If you can't find the right tool in this garage, Mr. Arizona...
如果在这里 还找不到顺手工具的话
you don't belong near a car.
那你根本没资格拥有车子
You don't belong near a car.
He owns you now.
你是他的人了
Tell me what you think about this.
告诉我你的想法
Koni adjustables.
换成可调整的哥尼牌避震器
Gonna save us about two pounds.
就能帮我减少两磅的重量
And they're gonna give us better traction for the hole shot.
而且还能增加车轮的防滑性能
All right?
好
This is your basic layout of the car...
这是这部车的基本设计
and that's pretty much what it could look like when it's finished.
而那就是整理好后的成品
Red, green.
红绿相间
Man, you should be going to MIT or something.
天呐  你该进麻省理工学院
Yeah, right.
想得美
No, I got that... Oh, what's it called?
我得了…他们叫什么来着？
- That attention disorder... - ADD?
- 就是注意力无法集中… - 所谓的ADD
Yes, that shit. Yeah.
对  就是那玩意
You know, I was good in algebra and, like, math...
其实我的代数很好
and shit.
也很喜欢数学
Everything else I failed.
可惜其他科目全都一塌糊涂
Dropped out of school. I don't know.
最后惨遭退学
It's just something about engines...
但是不知道为什么
that calms me down, you know?
只有引擎能够使我平静下来
- I'm outta here. - Come on, dog.
- 我走了 - 别这样嘛
Vince, get over here and give us a hand.
文斯  来这边帮我们一下
Looks like you got all the help you need, brother.
老大  你根本不缺帮手嘛
- Mia! - All right already.
- 蜜雅！ - 来啦
- The chickers dry. - I'm coming out already.
- 鸡肉都烤干了 - 我马上就来
Hey, hold up.
等一等
Because you were the first out of everybody here...
因为你是所有人中
to reach in to get the chicken, you say grace.
第一个拿烤鸡的 所以由你说祈祷文
Dear heavenly, uh...
亲爱的神圣的…
Spirit.
圣灵
Spirit. Thank you.
圣灵  谢谢你
Uh, thank you for providing us with a direct port...
嗯  谢谢你供应给我们
nitrous, uh, injection...
氧化亚氮喷气嘴
four core intercoolers and ball-bearing turbos...
还有进气冷却器 和滚珠轴承涡轮增压器
and, um, titanium valve springs.
还有  嗯  镀钛活门弹簧
- Thank you. - Amen.
- 谢谢你 - 阿门
- Not bad. - Amen.
- 很不错 - 阿门
He was praying to the car gods, man.
他根本是在向车神祈祷
- These are the best. - What do you want?
- 这些烤鸡真好吃 - 你要什么？
- Practice. - Thank you, girl.
- 练习呀 - 谢谢你  宝贝
Look who it is.
看是谁回来了
Old Coyotes 'R' Us.
咱们的老朋友
I thought you werert hungry, pumpkin.
我还以为你不饿呢
- You know, I gotta eat. - He's always hungry.
- 总得吃东西嘛 - 他永远吃不饱
All right, sit down.
好  快坐下来
How you doing, Mia?
蜜雅  你好吗？
- Jesse, hand me that chicken. - Let's eat some grub.
- 杰西  把烤鸡给我 - 让咱们吃个够
- Want some of that chicken? - Did you rent a movie or something?
- 还要不要再来点烤鸡？ - 有没有租录影带？
Need a hand?
你需要帮忙吗？
No, I'm good. You can go join the boys watching the movie.
不用了 你去和他们一起看录影带吧
Well, the cook doesn't clean where I come from.
在我家是不让厨子善后的
I'd like to go there.
那我真希望能去那里
I think we should go out sometime.
其实我们应该出去走走
No, I don't date my brother's friends.
我不和我哥哥的朋友约会
That sucks.
不会吧
- I guess I'll have to kick his ass then. - I'd love to see that one.
- 看来我得踢他几脚 - 那我倒想看
No, I would... I would pay to see that one, actually.
就算要付钱我也心甘情愿
Wash my car when you get done.
你忙完后就去替我洗车
- What was that? - No, Mia.
- 你是什么意思？ - 蜜雅  我不是说你
I'm talking to the punk.
我是指那个讨厌鬼
And wear your favorite dress, 'cause when you're done.
还有把你最好的洋装穿上
I'm putting you on the street where you belong, cutie.
因为等洗完车后你就该去接客了
Is this thing broken?
这个微波炉坏了吗？
What's wrong with this thing?
到底是怎么搞的
V, what was that Cuban restaurant you wanted to take me to?
文斯  你要带我去的 那家古巴餐厅叫什么名字？
The one with the peccadillo and the...
就是那间很有特色的餐厅
- Red candles and the wooden table? - Yeah, the plantain too.
- 有木头桌子上面放着红蜡烛 - 对  还有芭蕉树
- What was it called? - Cha Cha Cha.
- 那家叫什么名字？ - 叫恰恰恰餐厅
Yeah, that's it.
对  就是那家
Well, you can take me there.
你可以带我去那里
Friday night at 10:00. Is that good for you?
星期五晚上十点  可以吗？
- Yeah, it's perfect. - Good.
- 绝对没问题 - 那好
- There's no popcorn? - Make your own goddamn popcorn!
- 怎么没有爆米花 - 要吃自己去做
All right. Now that's valet parking.
好啦 这比代客泊车还方便
- Harry. - What's up, dog?
- 哈瑞 - 你最近好吗？
Excellent, brother. Come on in, man.
托你的福  很好  快请进
- Check it. It's yours. - What do we got here?
- 这些货你看喜不喜欢 - 这位又是谁呀
- Hired some new help, huh? - Don't even think about it.
- 新雇的帮手吗？ - 少挖苦我了
- What's up, Hector? - How you feeling?
- 海克特  近来好吗？ - 你怎么样？
Pretty good. What do you need?
很好  你需要些什么？
I need you to hook me up. Three of everything. I made a list.
你帮我照着这张单子找 每样要三个
Why don't you look that over.
你先看看
- When do you need this stuff by? - Tomorrow. Today.
- 什么时候要？ - 明天  今天也行
- Now. - Right.
- 现在更好 - 好
White boys work fast, don't they? Beto.
白小子动作蛮快的 贝多  把钱给我
That's right.
很好
You said you need three of all this?
“本田喜美” 你说每样要三个吗？
Yeah, three of everything. What do you think about that?
对  每样要三个  有办法吗？
Check this out.
你先看我手里的东西
He moans like a cop.
他连呻吟都像警察
Brian, this is one of those times...
布莱恩  这是关键时刻
when you need to be very clear about what you say.
要非常注意你所说的话
Nod if you understand me.
如果懂的话就点头
Nod!
快点头！
Sit up.
坐起来
Tell me what the hell you're doing down here.
你到这里来干什么
Oh, shit. What I'm doing.
我之所以来这里…
I owe... I owe you a ten-second car.
是因为我还欠你一部极速跑车
And what this is about, this is about Race Wars.
并且和极速大赛有关
I just went in there, and Hector is gonna be running...
我在里面发现
three Honda Civics with Spoon engines.
海克特有三部本田喜美 而且装上史普恩牌的引擎
And on top of that, he just came into Harry's...
除此之外  他还到哈瑞那里
and he ordered three T-66 turbos...
订购三个T66涡轮压缩引擎 加上氧化亚氮燃料注入器
with NOS, and a MoTeC system exhaust.
和莫德克牌电脑控制系统
So, what are you saying?
照你这么说
You're gonna go around and check everybody's shit out...
你要偷进每个人的车库里
one garage after another?
去查他们将要开什么车吗？
Yeah.
对
Because Dom, you know...
因为老大  你是知道的…
I can't lose again.
我不能再输了
He's a cop.
他是警察
He's a cop!
一定是警察
You a cop?
你是警察吗？
Let's go for a little ride.
咱们出去逛逛
Walk!
走呀！
All right, kid, stand watch.
杰西  你守在这里
喂  老大
There's no engines.
全都没有引擎
What are they planning on racing with? Hopes and dreams?
那他们拿什么来比赛？ 希望和梦想吗？
I don't know, but I know they're sneaky as shit...
不知道 我只知道他们狡猾得很
and they've got enough money to buy anything.
而且钱也不是问题
What?
什么事？
Dom, we got a wolf pack.
唐  他们来啦
It's Johnny Tran, and he's comiryour way really fast!
强尼和他那伙人 朝你那里去了  速度很快
All right, we got company.
有人来了  快躲
Spilner!
布莱恩！
Come on. Move!
走  快走！
Let me ask you a question, Ted.
泰德  让我问你一个问题
Do you see anything wrong here?
你有没有看出那里不对劲
No
没有
- We got no engines, do we? - No!
- 这里有没有引擎？ - 没有
- Do we? - No!
- 有没有？ - 没有
Nissan SR-Twenty motors will pull a premium one week before Race Wars, huh?
不是说在极速大赛前一个礼拜 就能拿到日产SR-20的引擎吗
Yeah, probably.
有可能
You're a smart fence, Ted. Maybe too smart.
你真会讲话 或许是太会讲话了
What are you feelir, Lance?
蓝斯  你觉得哪种好？
Forty weight?
密度四十的机油？
Fifty weight?
还是密度五十的机油？
A forty weight sounds nice.
四十的应该不错
Where are they, Ted? Where are they?
它们到底在哪里？ 你最好说实话
- Enough! - Where are they?
- 够了！ - 它们在哪里？
They're in a warehouse.
在仓库里
They're in a warehouse, man!
它们在仓库里
Kiss my shoes?
泰德  过来亲我的鞋子
Let's go get our engines.
咱们去拿引擎
My superiors are flying in from D.C. Day after tomorrow.
后天我的上司 会从华盛顿到这里来
I want something to show. Now, we have a top-echelon fence...
我一定得拿些成果给他看 到现在为止我们手上的资料是
with a lube hose in his mouth, automatic weapons...
一个嘴塞润滑剂管 油嘴滑舌的人  一些自动武器
a jacket full of priors on every one of these Asian punks...
一群亚裔帮派
a garage full of DVD players and generally psychotic behavior.
满满一车库的DVD放映机 还有一堆发疯的行为
Why not move on Tran now, see where we are when the dust settles?
何不先向强尼下手 等尘埃落定后再决定下一步
Because all we have is behavior. Let me get some hard evidence...
因为我们只掌握到情况 并没有有力的证据
because what we have now is circumstantial...
我们手上所有的 都不是主要的证据
What we have is probable cause and truckers arming themselves...
我们已经知道动机
for some good old vigilante mayhem.
和卡车司机准备自己组织 对抗暴力的自卫队
Tell us about Hector.
告诉我们海克特这个人
Latinos with spear guns. Give me a break.
他是拉丁人  一个小角色
Hector's still working on the engines for the cars...
他仍在替车子装引擎
but the tires don't match.
但是轮胎不合
Will someone just give me a cigarette?
谁有香烟  给我一根
- Get him a cigarette. - Don't get him a cigarette.
- 快给他一根香烟 - 别给他香烟
- I thought you quit. - Yeah, I did quit.
- 你不是戒烟了吗 - 是戒了
- Just give me a cigarette. - Get him a cigarette.
- 给我一根烟行不行 - 快给他香烟
No
别给他
- Tell me about Toretto. - He's too controlled for this.
- 杜洛托这个人呢？ - 他不像会做这种疯狂事情的人
I mean, what? Going suicidal on semi trucks? No way.
他应该不会做这种 自杀式的卡车抢劫行为
I mean, maybe his buddy Vince, but he's too stupid to pull it off.
文斯也许会做 但他不够聪明去策划它
I think the kid sister's blurring your vision.
我想那家伙的妹妹 蒙住了你的眼睛
- What do you say? - I don't blame you.
- 你是什么意思？ - 我不怪你
I'd get off on her surveillance photos too, buddy.
监视她也是我的一大享受
Knock it off. What? Are you going native on me, Brian?
别打了  你也喜欢动粗了吗？
Have you read Toretto's file lately?
你最近看过杜洛托的档案吗
- Yeah. I memorized that file. - Yeah, well, read it again.
- 我已经全都记住了 - 再看一遍吧
No. Better still. Take a look at these.
你最好看看这些资料
Remember I told you about the guy he nearly beat to death?
记得我曾经告诉过你 他几乎打死一个人吗？
Toretto did this with a 3/4-inch torque wrench.
他是用三分之四英寸的扭力板手 打伤那个人的
He's a model of self-control.
这就是他的典型自我控制力
I need a few more days.
再给我几天时间
我还需要几天时间
I need a few more days.
What it's gonna do is it's gonna spool up.
它将会从下向上卷
I got this set up for 24 psi.
我把最大操纵压力设在24
You got big plans tonight?
听说你今晚有个大计划？
Yeah. We're going out to dinner.
对  我邀蜜雅去吃晚餐
You break her heart, I'll break your neck.
你若伤她的心 我就扭断你的脖子
That's not gonna happen.
那种事绝对不会发生
I wanna show you something.
我给你看样东西
Wow.
哇！
Me and my dad built her.
是我和我爸爸改装的
900 horses of Detroit muscle. It's a beast.
九百马力的大马力跑车 它是个野兽
- Know what she ran in Palmdale? - No. What did she run?
- 你知道她在棕榈谷跑多快吗？ - 多快？
Nine seconds flat.
九秒跑四分之一英里
- God. - My dad was driving.
- 天呀 - 是我爸爸在开
So much torque the chassis twisted coming off the line.
扭力是那么的强 车身的底盘差点就脱离了
Barely kept her on the track.
而且非常难控制她
- So what's your best time? - I've never driven her.
- 那你能开多快？ - 我从来没开过
Why not?
为什么？
Scares the shit out of me.
因为她让我害怕
That's my dad. He was coming up in the pro stock car circuit.
那是我爸爸 当时他参加职业改装车大赛
Last race of the season.
是那一季的最后一场比赛
A guy named Kenny Linder came up from inside in the final turn...
一个叫肯尼的家伙 在最后转弯时从内线冲出来
and clipped his bumper and put him into the wall at 120.
碰到他的保险杠 让他在时速120时失控撞墙
I watched my dad burn to death.
我亲眼看着我爸爸被烧死
I remembered hearing him scream.
我还记得他的呼喊声
The people that were there said he had died before the tanks blew.
那里的人说 在油箱着火前他已经死了
They said it was me who was screaming.
而喊叫声是出自于我
I saw Linder about a week later.
事后大约一个星期我看到肯尼
I had a wrench, and I hit him.
手上刚好有个扳手 就用它去揍他
And I didn't intend to keep hitting him...
我并无意拼命的打他
but by the time I was done, I couldn't lift my arms.
但当我停下来时 手臂连举都举不起来
He's a janitor at a high school.
他在中学里做工友
Has to take the bus to work every day.
每天搭巴士上下班
And they banned me from the tracks for life.
从此以后 他们不准我参加任何赛车比赛
I live my life a quarter-mile at a time.
如今我是今朝有酒今朝醉
Nothing else matters... not the mortgage, not the store...
其他都无关紧要
not my team and all that bullshit.
什么贷款、店的生意 和我的那帮人  全都不重要
For those ten seconds or less...
只有赛车时的短短十秒钟
I'm free.
刹那间我彻底的解脱了
So how is it, anyways, that the gang came to be?
这个帮派是怎么组成的？
- What? - The gang.
- 什么？ - 这个帮派
The gang? No, they don't call themselves a gang.
他们不把它叫做帮派
- What do they call themselves? - They're a team.
- 那该怎么称呼呢？ - 他们称之为团队
- They call themselves a team. - How is it the team came to be?
- 他们叫自己为团队 - 这个团队是怎么组成的呢？
Well, that's a whole lot of history.
说来话长
I've got time.
我有的是时间
Vince grew up with my brother.
文斯和我哥哥一起长大
He didn't ever actually grow up, as you can tell.
可惜他一直不成熟
But they were friends as kids. And Letty, she lived down the street.
他们从小就是朋友 至于莱蒂是我们的邻居
Always into cars, though, ever since she was ten years old.
早在她十岁时就对车子着迷了
So, naturally, my brother always had her attention.
所以我哥哥自然引起她的注意
- And then she turned 16... - And then she had Dom's attention.
- 当她十六岁时… - 她却引起你哥哥的注意
Yeah. Yeah, it's funny how that works, isn't it?
对  这种事是不是很好玩
Yeah.
的确
How is it thatJesse fits into the whole thing?
杰西又是怎么加进来的呢？
Well, Jesse and Leon just sort of showed up one night...
杰西和李昂这两个家伙
and never ever left.
有天突然出现后就不走了
It's just the way my brother is. Dom's like...
其实这和我哥哥有关 他像是…
He's like gravity.
他像是一块磁铁
Everything just gets pulled to him.
把大家都吸引进来
Even you.
你也一样
No
不是
The only thing that pulled me in was you.
吸引我的是你
Being friends with your brother is just a bonus.
和你哥哥做朋友是额外的奖金
That's good.
很好
That's good. That's nice to come first every once in a while.
偶尔能排在第一位 感觉上倒是很棒
You wanna go for a drive?
我们去兜风好吗？
- Yeah? - The hijackers have hit again.
- 喂？ - 又发生抢案了
Bilkins made his decision. We're gonna move onJohnny Tran...
比金已经决定在下午五点
and his guys at 1700 hours, unless you say otherwise.
向强尼和他的手下动手 除非你有异议
If you agree, just say yes.
如果同意就说“是”
- Yeah. - Who is that?
- 是 - 那是谁呀？
Just a wrong number.
打错号码的
Yes, sir. Yeah, I know, but...
是的  长官  我知道  可是…
Yeah, yeah. Yes. Yes, sir.
是…长官
Yeah. I got it.
是的  我知道了
The DVD players were purchased legally.
DVD放映机都是合法购买的
All we've got on Tran and company are a couple of weapons charges...
我们只能告强尼和他的党羽 非法持有武器
and some outstanding speeding tickets.
和几张超速罚单而已
- So they're out. - Yeah. Father bailed 'em out.
- 所以他们都出狱罗 - 是他爸爸来保释他们的
Is this the kind of intelligence I can expect from you, O'Conner?
奥康纳 你的智商只有这么一点吗？
- You're gonna put this on me? - I can put it on whoever I want to.
- 你想怨到我头上 - 我想怨谁就怨谁
- Perks of the job. - No way you're gonna put this on me.
- 这是我的权力 - 你根本怨不到我
Wait a minute. Let me tell you.
安静点  你最好听清楚
I don't care if you have to put a gun to someone's head...
不管你用什么方法
and blow your cover to smithereens.
就算暴露身份我也不在乎
You got 36 hours to crack this bastard...
限你在36小时内把案子了结
or you might wanna be thinking about another career.
否则请你另就高明
It's Toretto, Brian. It always has been Toretto.
是杜洛托  绝对是杜洛托
Tran and Hector are... They're just fumes.
强尼和海克特只是烟雾而已
Well, I know you've been lying to me. My question is this:
我知道你一直在骗我 问题是
Have you been lying to yourself because you can't see past Mia?
你有没有因为 蜜雅的关系也在骗自己
He won't go back to prison.
他绝不愿意再回牢里去
Well, that's a choice he's going to have to make.
坐不坐牢要他自己去决定
There's all kinds of family, Brian.
世上有各式各样的人
That's a choice you're gonna have to make.
而你必须做个选择
You ready for this, jumpy?
紧张大师  准备好了吗？
Yeah.
好了
Nice car. What's the retail on one of those?
好车  市价是多少？
More than you can afford, pal. Ferrari.
老兄  你可负担不起 这可是法拉利
Smoke 'im.
赢过他
- So what's wrong, Brian? - Nothir, man. I'm fine.
- 有什么事不对劲吗？ - 没什么  我很好
Come on. Obviously something's off.
少装蒜了 显而易见的你有心事
Look. I have my good days, and I have my bad days, like anybody else.
我也和别人一样 心情有好有坏
Brian, don't lose that cool. That's your meal ticket.
别失去你那股酷劲 那才是你的饭票
My meal ticket? What? I can't pay for my own shrimp?
我的饭票 我连自己的车都负担不起
- I got your shrimp. - That's one thing about me.
- 我已经替你改装了一部车 - 你看这就是我的毛病
You don't understand. I don't need handouts. I don't take handouts.
我不接受别人的施舍
I earn my way, every step.
我要自己去赚
I just gotta make a little something extra on the side, like you.
我必须另外赚些外快 就像你一样
What do you mean, like me?
像我一样  这是什么意思？
- What's that supposed to mean? - That's what I mean.
- 你言下之意是什么？ - 那就是我的意思
- What does that mean, like me? - Don't try...
- 像我一样  你在说什么 - 别想…
I'm not stupid, all right?
我不是傻瓜
I know there's no way you paid for all that shit under the hood...
你改装车子所花的那些钱…
There's no way you paid for all that shit under the hood of those cars...
老实说你改装车子所花的钱
by doing tune-ups and selling groceries.
光靠替人调整引擎 和卖杂货绝对不够
Now, whatever it is you're in on, I want in on it too.
不管你的副业是什么 我要参加一份
- What is this? - Read it.
- 这是什么？ - 你自己看
- What is this for? - It's directions.
- 这是干什么？ - 那是地图
To Race Wars. We'll see how you do.
到极速大赛场的地图 先看你的表现
Then we'll talk.
别的以后再谈
(不准进入  基地关闭 美国政府资产)
- How's it goir, bro? - What's up, man?
- 兄弟  你好吗？ - 你好
Welcome to Race Wars.
欢迎参加极速大赛
Great. Thanks a lot.
很好  谢谢你
Baby. Hey, baby.
嘿  宝贝
You should watch from the side. I wouldn't want to get exhaust on you.
美女  你应该到观众席上去 否则会被排气喷得满身都是
- Put your money where your mouth is? - How 'bout I race you for that ass?
- 少贫嘴  有钱再说话 - 那咱们就赌你的美臀如何？
You want ass, why don't you hit Hollywood Boulevard?
想找女人好莱坞大道上多得是
You want an adrenaline rush, it'll be two large.
若想来一小段刺激赛 赌注是两千
Right here, right now. What's it gonna be?
就在此时此地  你敢吗？
You got it.
好  就这么决定
Another one bites the dust.
又一个送财美人
Come on. What do you got? What ya got?
让我看看你有什么本事
See ya.
等会儿见
Whoa. Bri, what's up? Whoa. Bri, what's up?
布莱恩  怎么样？ 布莱恩  怎么样？
What's up, Jesse? What do you have in your hand?
杰西  你怎么了？ 你手里拿着什么？
Throwing down the pink slip, just like you.
学你呀  这是车主证
- The pink slip to what? TheJetta? - Yeah.
- 车主证？是那辆捷达车吗？ - 对
- You can't bet your dad's car. - It's all right.
- 你不能拿你爸爸的车来赌 - 没关系
I ain't losing. This fool is running a Honda 2000. I'll win.
我一定会赢 那家伙开的是本田2000
That way, me and my dad can roll together when he gets out of prison.
我赢的话 等我爸出狱后手上就会有点钱
They're gonna throw him right back in prison after he kills you.
等他杀了你后  又得回牢里去
Shit. I'm up.
放心  我一定会赢
Visualize the win. Visualize the win, Jesse.
想像你得到胜利 杰西  一定要想像你得到胜利
- I'm serious. Listen to me, man. - Who you racing?
- 这很重要  你一定要听我的话 - 你的对手是谁？
Don't do it. I bet you he's got more than a hundred grand under the hood.
别和他赌  我保证他绝对 投资了好几十万在那部车上
Too soon, junior.
小子你太早了
Shit!
该死！
Oh, God.
喔  天呀！
Heads up, bro. We got problems.
快来  我们有麻烦了
- What? - Jesse.
- 什么事？ - 是杰西
- Where's Jesse going? - He just raced Tran for slips.
- 他要去哪里？ - 他刚拿车主证和强尼赛车
Oh, shit.
真要命
- Where's he going? - He went to the car wash.
- 他到哪里去了？ - 他去洗车
Whatever. Go fetch my car.
去把我的车子拿来
Go fetch your car? We're not on your block anymore.
你的车？ 现在可不是在你的地盘上
You'd better watch who you talk to like that.
看清楚你在和谁说话
SWAT came into my house, disrespected my whole family...
霹雳小组突击我家 使我家族受辱
because somebody narced me out.
那是因为有人出卖我
And you know what? It was you!
出卖我的人就是你！
Go! Let him go!
放开他！
Get off of him! Get off of him!
把他拉走  别打了！
Dom, chill out, man. Come on. Let's go.
唐  冷静点  咱们走
I never narced on nobody! I never narced on nobody!
我从没出卖过任何人
Mia!
蜜雅！
- I'm asking you not to go. - I'm doing this for both of us.
- 求求你不要去 - 我这么做是为了我们俩
Don't give me that crap. You're doing this for you.
胡说  是为了你自己
- Why are you asking me to stay? - Why do you insist on doing this?
- 为什么你不让我去呢？ - 你为什么一定要去呢？
Dom, please, don't.
唐  求求你别去
- What's going on? - What?
- 蜜雅  怎么回事？ - 什么怎么回事？
- You know what I'm talking about. - No, I don't, Brian.
- 你知道我在说什么 - 不  我不知道
So what? You always have tears in your eyes when Dom drives away?
难道每次唐开车走时 你都会眼眶红红的吗？
- What is the matter with you? - Come on.
- 你是怎么搞的嘛？ - 别装了
What's your brother racing off in the middle of the night for?
半夜三更你哥哥会去哪里呢？
I'm talking about the trucks. You know about the trucks?
是不是和卡车有关 你说是不是？
No, Brian. What trucks?
什么卡车  你在说什么？
Jesus Christ.
烦死人了
- What? - Listen to me.
- 又怎么了？ - 你听我说
Mia, I'm a cop.
蜜雅  我是个警察
What are you talking about, Brian? What is this?
你在胡言乱语什么
Ever since the first time I met you, I've been undercover.
当我们第一次见面时 我就是卧底警探
I'm a cop.
我真的是警探
You bastard.
你这个混蛋
去你的
Get off of me, Brian!
放开我！
Listen to me!
你听我说
Everything I ever said I felt about you was real, I swear to God.
我可以对天发誓 我对你的感情是真实的
You have to believe me. But right now, this isn't about you and me.
你一定要相信我 但现在的问题是你哥哥
Your brother's about to pull a job, and we're almost out of time.
你哥哥正要去做案 而我们的时间不多了
Those truckers, they're not laying down anymore.
那些卡车司机 不会再束手就擒
They may make it through the night, but every law enforcement agency...
也许今晚他们能得手
in California is coming down on 'em.
但是加州所有的执法人员 都会盯上他们
If you don't want anything to happen to your brother, to Letty...
如果你希望你哥哥、莱蒂 李昂、文斯都能安全无恙
to Leon, to Vince, you have to just get in that car with me right now.
最好现在就和我一起走
You have to help me.
你一定要帮我
Mia, you are the only person that can help me right now.
你是唯一能帮我的人
Please, Mia. Please help me.
求求你帮助我
Civics are stashed somewhere outside ofThermal.
本田车藏在 某处加热锅炉厂的外面
They wouldn't double back. And Highway 10's too well-patrolled...
他们是不开回头路的 而十号公路上又有警察在巡逻
so what does that leave us with then?
那我们得到什么结论
That leaves us with all this.
这就是我们的结论
- Nextel. - Yes, this is Officer O'Conner...
- 手机服务 - 我是奥康纳警探
serial number 34762.
编号是34762
I need a cell phone trace.
我需要追踪一个手机号码
- What's the cell number? - Mia, what's the cell phone number?
- 手机号码是什么？ - 蜜雅  手机号码呢？
Come on, Mia. She needs Dom's cell phone number now.
她现在需要唐的手机号码
323-555-6439.
323-555-6439
Thank you. You get that?
谢谢你  你听到了吗？
All right. We're one man short. Letty, I need you on the left side.
我们少了一个人 所以莱蒂你要开车
Your sister's right about this one. This don't feel good.
你妹妹说的没错 似乎是有点不对劲
Don't do that.
别这么说
- Something's wrong. - Stop.
- 真的好像有问题 - 别说了
We shouldn't be doing this without Jesse.
我们应该等杰西的
Look. This is the mother lode. We've been on this for three months.
这是个大金矿 我们已经盯了三个月
After this, it's a long vacation for everyone.
做完这次  大家都可以放长假
- Let's go. - I hope so.
- 走吧 - 希望如此
Listen. The other night I had a dream that you and I...
有一天晚上我做了个梦
were on a beach in Mexico.
梦见我们俩在墨西哥的海滩上
- Really? - Really.
- 真的吗？ - 真的
Come on. Let's make this happen.
走  先把这件事搞定
- Keep on those scanners. - Copy that.
- 注意扫瞄器 - 知道了
All right. Let's go.
好  我们出发吧
Yeah?
喂
We traced the number to the northbound 86...
那个手机号码在86号公路北向
mile 114 outside Coachella.
在科切拉之外 英里程标114的地方
- We'll keep the trace open. - Let me see this.
- 我们会继续追踪 - 我来看一下地图
All right. I think we're about 40 miles away.
我们离他们大约40英里
What are you gonna do?
你打算怎么做呢？
你到底想怎么做
Okay! Go time!
好  开始行动
We're all good, man. I got nothing on the scanners.
情况不错 扫瞄器上什么也没有
Keep going.
继续注意
Don't! Get back in!
文斯  快回来！
- He's got a damn shotgun! - Back off! Get him off of there!
- 司机居然有猎枪 - 退后  把他弄下来
Shit.
该死
Get me off this thing! Pull up!
把我弄下来  靠近点
- Unook yourself! - Come back!
- 你先把钩子松开 - 回来
- Do it! - Pull up!
- 快松开 - 靠近点！
- I can't... - You can do it!
- 我不能… - 你能的
Pull up! I'll jump!
你一靠近我就跳
Come on!
快点！
I'm pulling up to distract him.
我去分散他的注意力
Come on, boy.
你们加油呀
Shot doesn't get better than this.
开枪哪有赛车刺激
Son of a bitch!
混蛋  你居然真开枪
Take me off of here. I'm gonna unook the wire.
帮我离开这里 我先把金属线松开
Try it again. One, two, three!
再试一次  一、二、三
Unook yourself!
先把线松开
- I can't get my arm free! - Vince, grab my hand!
- 我的手臂被缠住了 - 你抓住我的手
- My arm! - Listen! Give me your hand!
- 我的手臂！ - 听着  把你的手给我
- I can't get my hand free! - I'm gonna pull you off!
- 我的手被缠住了 - 我会拉你过来
Dominic, hold on! Listen to me!
唐老大  千万别放弃我
Shit!
要命！
Hold on!
坚持下去
Move out of the way! I'm coming to get him!
你走开  我去帮他
- Yo? - Pull back for Letty.
- 莱蒂！ - 李昂  你回去帮莱蒂
- Get her out of there! - I'm on it! Go!
- 把她带走 - 我马上去
I got her! You get Vince off that truck!
我去帮她  你把文斯救下来
Come on, baby.
莱蒂
You okay?
你没事吧
Come on, girl. You all right? Come on. Let me look at you.
你还好吗？让我看看
Come on. We gotta go. Let's go.
快  我们得走了
- Take the wheel! - What do you mean?
- 你来开车 - 你是什么意思？
Put your foot on the gas!
把脚踩在油门上
- What the hell are you gonna do? - I'm gonna get him.
- 你想干什么？ - 我去救他
- Put your foot on the gas! - Okay!
- 快踩油门 - 好！
- All right. Keep it steady. - I got it!
- 稳住车子 - 可以了
All right. Hold on, Vince!
文斯  坚持下去
He's having a hard time holding on! Get me a little closer!
他的情况不好  再靠近点
All right!
好
- Closer! - I'm moving in!
- 再靠进一点 - 我正在接近
Hold it right there!
好  保持这个距离
- Go! - You gotta hang in with me!
- 跳！ - 你要和我合作
We're gonna get you off this thing! Give me your arm!
我们会把你弄下去 把你的手臂给我
Look at me. Don't let go.
看着我  千万别放手
Come on, Vince! Throw this arm around me!
文斯  用手臂抱着我
Don't let go.
别放手
Come on, Vince! Get closer!
文斯！靠近点
Vince, get closer! Come on!
再靠近点
Here we go.
好了  你先下去
Gotta jump.
我要跳了
Shit.
糟糕
It's gonna be okay, baby. I love you.
宝贝  不会有问题的  我爱你
Watch her.
你去照顾她
Come on, Vince. Hang in there!
文斯  撑下去
If we don't get him to an ambulance in ten minutes, he's dead.
救护车得在十分钟内到达 否则他就死定了
- Hold this. Hold the pressure. - I got it.
- 你按着这里 - 我会的
Don't let go. Hold his arm up.
别放手  把他的手臂抬高
Yeah. Yeah, this is Officer Brian O'Conner.
我是奥康纳警探
I'm off-duty M.A.P.D.
现在不在职勤中
I need a life flight rollout right away.
我立刻需要一架救护直升机
My twenty is Highway 86, mile marker 147.
我的位置是在86号公路 英里程标147
I got one trauma victim, about 24 years of age, six foot...  maybe 200 pounds.
这里有一位重伤遇难者 大约24岁、六尺高、200磅
He's got a deep laceration to his right arm with arterial bleeding.
右臂的割口很深、动脉出血
And he's got a shotgun wound, close-range, to his left leg.
他的左脚被猎枪近距离射伤
Yeah.
是的
Yeah. And he's going into shock.
他刚进入休克状态
Put the gun down now!
唐  把枪放下来
- Move your car. - Bullshit. Put it down now!
- 把你的车开走 - 放屁  把枪放下来
- No more running. - I'm not running!
- 不要再逃了 - 我没有逃
- Where's Leon and Letty? - They're long gone.
- 李昂和莱蒂呢？ - 他们早就走了
Then it's over. I didn't call the police, but don't push me.
一切都结束了  我没叫警察 但别逼我
- Put the gun down! I swear to Go... - You are the cop!
- 把枪放下来  我发誓… - 你就是警察
You're a cop!
你就是警察呀！
Brian, I gotta find Jesse before they do.
我必须在他们之前找到杰西
- I'm all the kid's got. - I'll call in the plates.
- 这孩子只能靠我 - 我可以叫警方寻找他的车牌
P.D.'ll pick 'im up way before Johnny even gets near 'im.
一定会在强尼之前找到他的
- Move your car. - Dom, stop it! It's over! Please!
- 把你的车开走 - 拜托你们别吵了
Mia, stay out of it. Move the...
蜜雅  没你的事  把你的…
I am so sorry. I don't know what I'm doing.
唐  对不起 我不知道自己在做什么
I'm so scared right now. I don't know what's going on.
我吓得要死  不知道该怎么办
- What were you thinkir, man? - I don't know. I panicked.
- 杰西  你的脑袋在想些什么？ - 我吓呆了
I'm sorry. I don't know what I'm doing. Will you please help me?
我真不知道自己在干什么 求求你帮帮我
Jesse!
杰西！
Call 911. You, call 911!
叫救护车  你去叫救护车
I used to drag here back in high school.
当我念高中时常来这里
That railroad crossing up there is exactly a quarter-mile away.
从这里到平交道是四分之一英里
On green, I'm going for it.
绿灯一亮我就会冲过去
That's not what I had in mind.
我没料到会是这样的结果
You know what you're doing?
你知道自己在做什么吗？
I owe you a ten-second car.
我还欠你一部极速跑车
I live my life a quarter-mile at a time.
我是今朝有酒今朝醉
Nothing else matters.
其他都无关紧要
For those ten seconds or less...
只有赛车时的短短十秒钟
I'm free.
刹那间我彻底的解脱了